this problem requires us to
modify the given code so that the string
hello
is printed five times first let's
examine the code
that we've been given on line one we've
initialized a local variable say hello
referencing the boolean value true
on lines three through six we have a
while loop
and the condition provided to this while
loop is the variable say hello
the way that this works is while the
value of the variable say hello
is truthy the loop will execute
if the value of the sayhello variable is
falsy
iteration will stop so initially
sayhello references the boolean true
which is truthy so the loop begins to
execute
on line four it outputs the string hello
on line five say hello is reassigned
to false and of course false is falsy
so now when ruby reaches the top of the
loop again on line three
because the value of say hello is falsey
the loop stops executing as this code is
currently written
the loop will only iterate and output
hello one
time and to see this in action i'm going
to run the code
the desired result here is actually to
output the string hello
five times knowing that we can determine
that we do not want to reassign
say hello to false every time this loop
runs
in order to control when we do want to
reassign the sayhello variable
we can use an if statement
now we need to use a condition for our
if statement
and one simple way to do this would be
to have a variable count
and when the value of count is equal to
reassign the variable say hello to false
now we need to initialize our local
variable count
and it needs to be initialized outside
of this loop
[Music]
if we were to initialize our account
variable
inside of our while loop it would be
reassigned to zero
each time we looped through and the loop
would become infinite
instead what we need to do is initialize
count in the outer scope
and increment it by one each time that
we
iterate through our loop so we'll
reassign count on line six
to the current value of count plus one
now looking at our code on lines eight
through ten
we can actually write our if condition
in shorthand syntax
[Music]
and now i'm going to run the code and
see if i'm getting the expected behavior
[Music]
and the string hello was output to the
screen five times which is exactly what
we wanted